<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Right to Counsel Jersey City</title><link>https://righttocounseljc.org/</link><description>Recent content on Right to Counsel Jersey City</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://righttocounseljc.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Right to Counsel for Tenants</title><link>https://righttocounseljc.org/post/right-to-counsel-for-tenants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://righttocounseljc.org/post/right-to-counsel-for-tenants/</guid><description>Landlords are removing New Jerseyans from their homes at the highest rate since the pandemic began. In response, the North New Jersey Chapter of the Democratic Socialists of America (NNJDSA) is organizing a campaign to pass a “Right to Counsel” (RTC) ordinance in Jersey City.
RTC refers to government policy that funds free legal representation for people at risk of losing their homes. Sometimes that risk is due to eviction filing, a landlord’s failure to make necessary repairs, harassment or discrimination by a landlord, or any circumstance that may put tenants at risk of being forced to move.</description></item><item><title>Right to Counsel Launch and Rally</title><link>https://righttocounseljc.org/post/launch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://righttocounseljc.org/post/launch/</guid><description>📈 Rent is skyrocketing
🏘️ Tenants are struggling to keep our housing
🏗 Corporate landlords are developing us out of our communities
We are excited to launch our Right-to-Counsel campaign in Jersey City! Right-to-Counsel is about ensuring tenants receive legal representation with no barriers. People should have the right to be protected from landlord harassment, from eviction to unsafe living conditions.
Join us Sunday, July 24th at noon by City Hall for the inaugural rally.</description></item><item><title>Right to Counsel FAQs</title><link>https://righttocounseljc.org/post/faq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://righttocounseljc.org/post/faq/</guid><description>What is the right to counsel?
The right to counsel is a legal guarantee that a tenant will be granted representation by an attorney before they are evicted from their home.
How effective is the right to counsel at preventing evictions?
Studies of the jurisdictions that have passed right to counsel laws all reveal benefits to tenants. When represented through RTC programs, tenants are much more likely to stay in their homes — as much as 41% — because lawyers can help tenants identify available defenses and resources like rental assistance programs.</description></item><item><title>About Right to Counsel</title><link>https://righttocounseljc.org/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://righttocounseljc.org/about/</guid><description>Nationwide, only 3% of tenants are represented in housing court, while for landlords that’s more like 81% on average. Housing is a human right and no one should have to fight for their homes without fair representation. It’s time to demand Jersey City level the playing field and reign in landlord power. Let&amp;rsquo;s join 15 cities and 3 states and pass right to counsel. To fight back against all eviction and displacement we need to guarantee the right to counsel for ALL tenants.</description></item><item><title>In the Media</title><link>https://righttocounseljc.org/in-the-media/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://righttocounseljc.org/in-the-media/</guid><description>Check out the coverage Right to Counsel JC&amp;rsquo;s gotten in the press!
The right to counsel: A moral imperative for Jersey City North N.J. DSA launches right-to-counsel campaign to aid Jersey City tenants</description></item><item><title>Take Action</title><link>https://righttocounseljc.org/take-action/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://righttocounseljc.org/take-action/</guid><description>We will be organizing city-wide canvasses and phonebanks and posting them here.
Nov 8 - Election Night Street Canvass
Saturday, Nov 12 - Canvass at Audubon Park
Saturday, Nov 19 - Canvass at Pershing Field
Sign up on our Action Network page to stay up-to-date.</description></item></channel></rss>